welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where we go here and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
yeah thanks that intro Peter it's great
to be here with all you guys
I think Peter did a very good summary of
what letters intentions are it is a
place to try and repair the problems
with discourse particularly online you
know we initially as a team started
working on that it because we noticed
that the signal-to-noise ratio on
platforms like Twitter and Facebook is
really poor you know there's there are
interesting perspectives on a number of
different issues but it's very difficult
to have a long form good-faith
conversation with someone on those
places and there's a number of reasons
why it's difficult a lot of it relates
to how all those platforms are designed
and what they tend to incentivize for
but a huge part of the problem is that a
otherwise productive conversation can be
derailed by anyone who wants to poke
their head into the dialogue so Peter
and I might be having a conversation on
something like Twitter and you know a
troll or anyone who wants to inject
their opinion into that space can do so
and there's often rewarded for doing so
like it's a way to signal to your
in-group some sort of virtue so we step
back we thought what is it that makes
conversation productive and meaningful
in the real world and how could we
design a space that replicated a lot of
those features so that their process
started so late in 2018 we managed to
launch the first version of letter early
in 2019 and since then there's just been
a series of experiments where can we
find people who are trying to have the
longer form more nuanced conversation
online
invite them onto letter and pair them up
with people to have the kinds of
conversations that are difficult to have
elsewhere and it's been really rewarding
to see the kinds of dialog that has
emerged on the platform there's a
tremendous amount of diversity of
thought there and I think the the
content is unique in the sense that it's
not just long-form but it's also a kind
of a stress testing of ideas as taking
place people are able to reach the
conclusions that they might not be have
been able to reach by themselves because
they are getting this instant feedback
or if not instant at least it's relative
relatively quickly so I could post to
someone and within a couple of hours or
a couple of days receive their views on
it and I can then spend some time
thinking about it so kind of bridges the
gap between there are kind of the
real-time nature of something like
Twitter and podcasts and kind of the
more old-fashioned letter exchanges with
across the ocean or so I think having
that there breathing room where you can
think about what you think and form your
arguments and make your points I think
is really important that's one of the
reasons why the calling of the dialogue
is so hot so you know Peter came on
board I think around
midway through 2019 we reached out to
him after Helen plaque rose mentioned
his mediator medium post and I read that
and go and just thought oh this is just
like the
it's like a playbook for how you could
connect people who want to invite a cue
leur ideology or an idea but might like
the right correspondence so yeah so the
platform as it sits right now is
evolving in really interesting ways and
one of them is Peters sort of
meditations that he's been doing he's
writing to himself I think how many days
has been now Peter that you've been
posting a daily meditation sixty so that
there's like blood on his fingers I'm
just like pounding away my friend yeah
so I mean it's it's it's something that
when we launched it now you have this
technology but you can't really imagine
all the ways in which it could be
utilized and this is a really
interesting use case that I'm sure we'll
get into on this chat you know one of
the things you said to me that I it
stood out a few days ago is that it's
been transformative and I wanted to ask
you about it at the time but I thought
hold off to have this conversation what
is it about it that has been
transformative so there's like a pre
commitment going into it is that I'm
gonna be absolutely truthful and I'm
gonna put myself at like what we're
calling here the knife's edge and we'll
put myself at the edge of like feeling
uncomfortable almost you know psych is
it like safe is it not safe to say
that's just like right at that edge so
those are only kind of two pre
commitments there and if there's like
this is the so projects been very
interesting and I went through some if
you've been reading it couldn't do like
a spiritual crisis halfway through and I
was just like writing while I was like
you know feeling almost like not part of
this world and it almost like kind of
kept me in reality in a way and then
knowing that there's a wider audience
you're even though I'm writing to myself
I know I'm writing to other people and
it's almost the lines of becoming of the
self either the concept of the self gets
expanded or the lines between myself and
other people still have kind of kind of
blurred a little bit so it's interesting
that spiritual component
of the writing exercise as well it's
very interesting I wonder what you've
learned not just from the self
journaling or like the writing to
oneself but the responses that you've
got anything in those that has been
particularly interesting or surprising
yeah like oh I'll just saw this other
great one that I got today actually so
what I really enjoy about letter is that
they don't have like a freaking comment
section or like a like so you know like
even though you guys showed me the stats
of how many people are reading it so I
know like how many people are reading it
and I don't know who's treating it you
know I have no idea who who's reading it
and I kind of liked that mystery going
on there not knowing who's reading and
so here's a guy so I'm getting these
random emails because then what I'm
doing is I'm sending a mailing list each
day with the upcoming events for
tomorrow and then I put the letter thing
and then people have been emailing me
personally responding to letters and I'm
getting a lot of emails this one today
is like Peter holy shit the last article
wasn't a fluke
your writing is consistently hilarious
insightful provocative riveting and then
you know he says if you can't donate to
the store because he's a broke-ass tram
and eating entrepreneur but he pitched
him what he can and so just like it's
such a like a heart like just getting an
intimate message like that is very
beautiful and a lot of people are
actually responding because a letter
platform allows you to respond to the
letter on the platform - and few people
respond to that as well like Bonita Roy
she challenged she didn't like the
challenge but she kind of added to
something which is very enriching so
it's more heartfelt and more feels more
real the feedback I'm getting from this
rather than just having a normal blog or
just on Twitter or whatever maybe you
could talk a bit about what the initial
impetus for the stoah was because I mean
we were obviously been talking about
letter related things and it came out of
nowhere for me but was it something you
were thinking about for a while yeah
I'll talk about it and then I'll do some
judo moves and bring the question back
to you okay I got a I got a few
questions about letter America mediation
so you know I was gonna open up a
philosophical coffee shop called the
stoah because I run the largest store
community here in Toronto as well as the
intellectual explores clubs I wanted a
home for it faith God I didn't open it
up because the cone Vidur which have
been closed right away and so I opened
up online present instead and it has
just been kind of like just flew picked
up and it's pretty exciting and like I
was telling you and Dane like I kind of
want to reinvent stoicism I want to give
it some soul I want to give it some sex
I want to give it some life I won't
allow it to become embodied and in order
to Andrea you know she's just getting it
right now she knows because a lot of the
modern stoic movement it just it feels
it's too much of a history lesson it's a
101 on stoicism constantly and there's a
disembodied quality to it even when you
hear some of the people speak it's like
you can't feel their fucking words they
all sound the same and so with this this
though I want a genuine wisdom Jim to
emerge from it where we can kind of
discover what stoicism is and practice
it together and become embodied so
that's sort of the goal is to reinvest
ilysm and then bring back practices or
find new practices like this writing
writing meditation and so one thing I
want to I want to flip it back to you
and if anyone has any questions for me
or Clyde just write it in the chat box
and we can kind of take you in but like
what so one thing that we're doing here
mimetic mediation we're having a
mediation campfire every every Saturday
3:30 p.m. Eastern time or we just gotta
gather around the digital campfire we
spit ball about like who should talk to
each other right like and then we're
kind of figuring out how to get them to
talk to each other in the wild and what
platform might be the best one is it as
a letter is it an empathy circle or
whatever and the idea is to bring all
these intelligent people that would not
normally talk to each other but make
them feel comfortable around the digital
campfire so they trust the Stoll they
trust us and then get them figure out
how to talk to each other right so it's
like a really long game approached in
mediation that we're doing here and when
I was working for letter that's all I
was doing I was I fucking like mimetic
mediation on specifically on the
platform so I'm curious cuz I haven't
really been plugged in how is that
coming along like what how does your
meet mimetic mediation efforts on letter
and how is that coming along so far I
mean it's the exciting thing is as a
we're having to do less sort of manual
outreach to produce conversations I
think one of the it's a feedback we got
from Y Combinator which is one of the
incubators we applied for was that you
really need organic growth to be onto
something at least you know from a
sustainability perspective it's it's one
thing to be able to reach out and to
match people up and it requires a kind
of deep domain knowledge of both parties
work to do that successfully it's one of
the reasons I think you were so good at
that Peter was it you the space that you
were swimming in you had a very deep
understanding of the different players
and their work and where they might
agree or disagree and how to connect the
right people is a it's a skill and when
you when you've sort of not left the
company but I've been able to not be
able to do as much work it's something
it's as a whole there we haven't been
able to fall in terms of the skill set
in the team that we we have now which
has been a double-edged sword one is we
saw a dip in the number of conversations
but the conversations that are appearing
are much more organic which is exciting
the the next sort of step for us as a
platform is to improve discoverability
of content I think it's really important
you know you might come into later
through a conversation that that's
shared on something like Twitter or
Facebook
but once you've read that exchange we
haven't done a good job in directing
people to other content that's likely to
be interesting to them and that's why
the last few months has been dedicated
to this topics epic that's Dana and Ryan
and Jackson and other team members have
been working on is Academy
we help channel people into new places
that it's going to show them content
that because we have great content we
just don't do a great job of
highlighting it one way is through this
this topics feature set which is coming
in the next couple of weeks but the
other is through the community pages so
as you mentioned it in the opening we're
going to be building a stellar page bond
letter and the idea there is that all
the content relating to and generated by
the members there will have a home and
you're really interested in getting
feedback once version one of that is
launched we can get your page up in the
next few days and start inviting people
and you know the biggest lesson I think
we've learnt as entrepreneurs try to
build something is that it really is a
the fundamental driver of change has to
be the readers the users there it isn't
the writers and ultimately you can't sit
in a dark room and plot what your next
exciting feature said is going to be
it's you've got to make your best guess
as to what you think is going to provide
the most value put it out into the world
and then iterate based on actual usage
so the exciting thing for us and in an
area where I think everyone on this call
that is going to be using the store I
can help us with is really identifying
bugs features that you want what do you
love about it but what is confusing
what's insured of that sort of feedback
I think people underestimate how
important it is you know just before
this call Peter we jumped on a couple of
community pages and there's got your
feedback about what what here do you
like what do you like what makes sense
and when you're as close to it as we are
building it you can miss things that is
obvious to the general user so once that
page launches I can't stress enough how
much we would love feedback
and so there was a YouTube page and then
since the community to again okay
there's a delay on your end but we heard
like it fries for about 10 seconds okay
yeah I think we got everything we said
they you ended off saying that um you
would love people's feedback for yeah
yeah your video is a little bit choppy
but you're still incredibly good-looking
so don't worry about it
so I guess the other students yeah we
have some questions but I do so Travis
messaged me a question he said what is
the the store page gonna look like and
maybe I can I can speak on that a little
bit there's like maybe you can add some
of the details in there there's gonna be
too broad just like a welcome page and
then just like so think of like you know
red it has like subreddits it's sort
like a love letter equivalent to that in
one one way and so there's going to be
like two broad sections where exchanges
that you see from the members select
Travis I think you and me or like we're
writing to each other about something
exploring a topic and then there's
another section where it's like the open
letter section where you're writing to
yourself as for like the spiritual
practice or you're just kind of and then
someone if they see a letter like your
letter that you wrote today they can
jump in right you and then that pops up
in the section where your the feed where
you see people writing with each other
so the idea is to have an ecology of
letters and ideas and members just kind
of engaging and putting each other at
the edge of our thinking to complement
this you know space that we have right
here is there anything that's perfect
and then I understood no I think that's
it i think the the evolution of the
platform is gonna be driven by by you
guys
we'll take a feedback to the designers
and the programmers and so Paul we have
a few questions for me but that Paul has
a question and he put her own caps well
you want to go off mute and ask it sorry
apologize you don't need to apologize to
start sorry so a lot of information
letters updates to letters follow-ups
there'll be some pity inside somewhere
in there and how would you um would you
put meta tags a lot of work someone
unique dedicated people to or the the
participants would add their own tags
somehow you need to be able to combine
this information so that you can
retrieve it is that a possibility yeah I
mean the simplest way is I compose flyer
for the learners so when you're
composing the letter you can list out
the topics that are going to be covered
and those topics can evolve over the
exchange so you might start off talking
about stoicism and sarcasm whatever it
is you're talking about but it has the
letter exchange unfolds you might shift
into other areas and you can continually
update the topics and what they will do
is sort the content into the relevant
areas so when I come into later and I
want to find content about stances of my
search for them appear well the content
about that will appear then over time
we'll be able to rank stuff based on how
popular it is who's reading this content
and yeah as you've mentioned it's a
tremendous amount of work but I think
the getting the initial phase of those
developments right requires as much
simplicity as possible and then over
time you can add the sophistication in
to the backend so it doesn't interfere
with the user experience but in
principle not none of the
discoverability problems
unsolvable it's you know it's and the
more data you have the quicker you can
you can move it's it's extremely
exciting thank you I mean everything in
with programming seems to move at a
glacial pace say I'm a non-technical
founder and it's like when can we have
this the answer is almost always months
I just have a question because there's
some questions for me and that might
just kind of change the direction to
radically at this point but like a
double-click on the humane tech
mentioned choice on Harris so I know
that's sort of you didn't go into letter
with that mindset that framework I don't
even know if you're aware of it at that
point but it came on your radar and you
know you had a conversation with Dristan
did you speak a little bit how you see
letter being involved in the broader
humane tech movement very much aligned
our mission is to enhance the quality
and impacts of conversation dialogue is
fundamental to solving any problem and
if we continue to create online spaces
that make dialogue more difficult or
more polarizing then we're going to be
doing humanity a great disservice and
think Humane Tech is kind of sits above
that as of the umbrella term for
developing technologies that actually
improve human flourishing and you know
we think that letter at scale could have
a ginormous impact when we reach that
the Tristana had already been he was
aware of that read some of the
conversations there and he discussed it
on a few podcasts and then a few talks
that he gave as an example of technology
that is heading us in a direction that
he'd like to see more of the challenge
for us like with any of these things is
that it's always going to be easier to
design platforms that sort of optimize
for our more basic impulses and our
simple so like it's always going to be
easy
to write a tweet easier to write a tweet
and it's going to be to write but we
think that the value that's produced in
those two domains is correlates with the
effort you know I think getting people
through the door the first time into a
letter exchange is the challenge I think
their lives are busy opportunity cost is
significant and they've got YouTube
they've got podcasts they've got TV
they've got all these competing things
we're presenting them is something
that's relatively difficult we're saying
sit down
clear your desk in your mind and
actually put your thoughts out into the
world in a long-form thoughtful in the
honest way and that that isn't
presenting users with minimal frictions
presenting them with quite a lot of
friction but I think we have to we have
to go down this road we can't just keep
producing sort of candy floss products
to go and raise a bunch of money in
Silicon Valley I think we need to figure
out a way to get people through the door
you know to give them that first
exchange because like a lot of things
you know I think we've used the
something like yoga if I just described
yoga to you in abstract terms you're
gonna walk into a room with a bunch of
strangers and for the next 90 minutes
you're going to hold difficult strange
poses and at the end of it you're gonna
walk out feeling invigorated and
refreshed and you might even turn it
into a practice a lot of people might
think you were crazy but that is the
writing and dialogue is somewhat akin to
that the challenge of course is that we
don't have thousands of years to bring
this aging practice to the mainstream
very great and we had to Joshua fields
on this morning he talked he's all about
leveraging technology in order to
cultivate wisdom and he had a talk on
like trauma truth and technology and his
argument is like a lot of our
interpersonal reaction or inter
relationships or kind of trauma basis
responding to this trauma that we have
and they have these unhealthy
relationships to it and I see the humane
tech movement kind of like adding
putting going to a positive direction
and in addressing that at least with the
kind of social media platforms and so I
think it's very stoic friendly for sure
so do you have any questions for me
Clyde or anything before we go to the
room yeah I'm interested in what you're
it may be first of all if you have one
what your pitch would be like what is
that you would tell someone like me who
isn't writing letters to myself or
anyone else that was curious about the
project that you're undertaking and walk
why should we do this what's the given
all the competing things I can do with
my time what's the best call to action
here why why would someone undertake
this writing to yourself each day yeah
yeah especially in a public I mean I can
understand sort of journaling yeah
really interested in how you saw this to
people what would you what's your the
greatest insights and the most value
that you've extracted from the
experience yeah yeah the the word cell
is throwing me off it's just it's
putting me in like salesman models just
shutting me down that one one frame but
so how do you bring this funny to other
people how's that reframing yeah yeah I
like that I like that I would say that
there is it's it comes down to being
truthful you know and there's many ways
to be truthful and many different
mediums like in a podcast or you know in
a public lecture or writing to yourself
and being truthful like modeling
truthfulness is really important today I
think because we're full bullshit and
and we're like in the meta crisis we're
in a pandemic
and we need to be truthful together in
order to figure out what the heck is
going on and what to do together and I
think being truthful on a medium such as
writing to yourself in a letter format
adds a different quality because it
slows down your mind you can relax and
then truths you discover truths that you
otherwise would not discover maybe in a
conversation or maybe when you're just
in broadcast mode and I think you you
should this thought with me when we were
in California how when you were
initially on the platform exchanging
doing letter exchanges these thoughts
just emerged to you that probably would
have never happened if it in a different
medium or maybe it would have but not in
the way it happened so I would have to
polish up that sales pitch but it'd be
something like that like you know
modeling truthfulness and then allowing
certain insights to emerge that the slow
thinking of letter writing allows for
this question is questions here I'm much
more if they're interest to you or my
other question for Peter do I knock out
some of these ones Peter that yeah so
everyone's been as stressed as my stores
right now I knew it's gonna happen
so if you got a question for me this
love story between you and stoicism
began yeah I was when I was in
university I took philosophy and they
didn't talk about sources at all just
like a 101 made mention and the first
class and then my friend at the time he
gifted me
Epictetus his handbook and I was like
what is this like this is the shit I get
really just grounded me because it's so
practical and and so I was drawn to
stoicism ever since and during my
darkness of the soul when I have
spiritual crises like I just turned to
sauces and this sort of my bedrock even
though like I it's like I'm kind of
weird like I don't know if I am a stoic
like someone asked me yesterday are you
really a stoic like like I don't really
care if I am or not but it's sort of my
permit is drawn to stoicism and it is I
am drawn to it in that my dark nights so
and it sort of like marketing according
to the sales I'm sort of just marketing
the stoah using the stoic brand type
thing but there's only two real Stoics
here if I am a real stoic me and Daniel
butts though is not really a place to
practice stoicism it's a place to
coherent dialog what matters most and if
a new form of stoicism can get
reinvented here great because the
majority the text stoked X like 90% of
them through history went missing that's
what I thought that's what I'm told and
then we don't really know how Stoics
actually practiced and then the tenants
it's just so like lean you know the
stoic philosophy it's so lean that it
can be prevented and repurposed I think
and that's what really excites me about
it cool very cool
now David you got you got a stress
testing question yeah so I just wanted
to push back on some of your recent
criticisms of stoicism it seems like
you're trying to differentiate your
brand or a reboot or fork off a stoicism
with an embodied version and you call
the more traditional yet modern stoicism
disembodied but I sort of interpret that
as intellectuals to assistant they would
definitely agree that they're rational
philosophy and intellectual and you use
disembodied almost like it's derogatory
and I don't think that they would agree
with that the modern Stoics it seems
like charitable it's like calling
embodied anti-intellectual so just want
to get your thoughts on that yeah it is
derogatory and it is unshared able I
totally I totally owned both of that and
propositional II if any of the martyr
stores and I danced we'd probably end up
agreeing more than we disagreed and you
know not going to name names and it's
not just for the stoic movement but a
lot of intellectual movement I feel
they're not really embodied thinkers and
what I mean by that they don't they're
they don't have a certain emotional
fluency they don't engage in kind of a
sort of we space or authentic where they
can type practices you don't really feel
their words when they speak and they
feel too much in their head and I think
a balance is needed and I still think
you can be guard your premises the
propositional in propositional integrity
with that and still feel embodied and so
it's more of like a personal attack I'm
doing on certain people I won't name and
it is unshared about did you wanna have
any follow-up to that David er sure I've
just still thinking that that's maybe
fundamental to stoicism is that
intellectual aspect but they might feel
the emotions or but they don't react to
them they respond to them there's
definitely a rational D component there
that you seem to you want to get rid of
and if you do that then I'm not sure
that what you have left is stoicism no I
don't wanna get rid of the rationality
component I'm a man of reason and I
think stoicism is great because if you
follow the algorithm you know it you
know what cards are acceptance
commitment therapy there's a cognitive
diffusion emerges where you can separate
yourself from your emotions you don't
get diffused by it and when I see a lot
of Stoics and intellectuals do they just
stay there now I think the project is to
turn back and build those relationships
with those emotions and allow you to
feel them fully and they're love them is
to kind of like be possessed by them in
a way without compromising your rational
muscle so yeah I'm not saying get rid of
rationality exceed oh you got it you got
a hand so you feel like you're gonna
pile in on this - no no I I'm loving I'm
loving your letters I'm loving your your
guts you know that that you're putting
out there and knowing you personally I
enjoyed them and I respect I think where
they're coming from the not knowing very
well but knowing you somewhat
how much of at the curious buy
Epicureanism and our Sicilian is coming
into your store sirs if any that's a
good question so Tito your practices
though so you're well I'm a student I'm
a student yeah so there's three of us
here at least mr. Davis's stoic too so
yeah they're some of us yeah I don't
know I don't know obviously I'm
influenced by them but I'm not
consciously thinking about them but as
you as you read like I'm influenced by
it so all these ideas and I let good
even if you read like Seneca and then
the original Stoics they talk about
engaging with other philosophies and
then sort of like talking with thumb and
challenging them and whatnot and being
challenged by them and even though I
would say stoicism my bedrock I just let
everything in and just dance with it so
we have a question from Travis about the
letter platform yeah so it's a put like
a little bit of clarification on it so
I'm asking how would somebody start like
how would you suggest that they start
and is that based on ease of starting or
most likely that the most likely method
by which the letters would continue
going back and forth and do you see any
difference with the various ways that
people start engaging in terms of how
long the correspondence lasts so it's
kind of a two-part question the first
one is like just how would you suggest
that people start in terms of like the
social norms that are evolving within
the letter platform like are people just
reaching out randomly to others
proposing a topic and saying let's talk
about this not randomly but you know
based on a loose connection or or some
other form and then which method have
you seen if you've done this analysis
leads to the longest correspondence you
know so
of getting started a lot of people are
taking conversations that they're having
offline with someone on to to flesh them
out and actually having them in writing
this is well I think the first letter
there was written on the platform was
between me and a friend of mine Mike
name and we've been having a
conversation for years essentially where
he would come to he lives in a different
state he would visit and we would get to
a sort of impasse then he would go home
and every time we reconnected we would
kind of discover the same ground we
weren't really getting anywhere so the
experiment was can we move this into a
written space and see if we can make
some progress and that was really
interesting because I think we got into
areas that we hadn't previously we
understood each other better
at the end of that exchange than we had
at the start so that was that's one use
case it's like I'm having this dialogue
offline let's see if we can make more
progress in a written format then the
other one is the impulses I've got
something that I want to say but I'm not
sure who the best person to have the
conversation with is in that instance
you can write an open letter on the
platform sort of outlining your thoughts
talking about what it is that you would
like to discuss framing your positions
and then anyone who reads that can
respond and then it's being match made
and that's kind of reaching out to us on
email saying I would like to have this
conversation with this type of person
and we can go out into the community and
try and find someone who's suitable and
connect you up that way in terms of the
length and how the initiation of the
conversation affects how long they go on
for it's very much an evolving thing we
have parties who define relatively tight
parameters at the beginning and decide
that
I'll have the opening letter I'll give
you the final word we'll stick to the
1000 word loads all right three letters
each and
wrap it up in a month so that that's
becoming quite common and then there are
other conversations that are over 50
letters long and have been going for
more than six months and there is no end
goal really it's just we both find this
interesting and this is a good way in
which to conduct these conversations and
maybe at some point we'll decide to draw
a line under it but there's no need to
do so and you know we're open to all of
that I think as a reader I think you
want to be excuse me as a writer you
want to be mindful of the reading the
readers experience it altima CLE depends
on what your goals are if the goals are
to reach a broader audience and to put
ideas you think are important to add
into the world and you are competing in
a short form with a lot of short form
spaces and I think getting to the point
clearing up any initial ambiguity and
being in fourth fourth right and I guess
I would say that you need to I had this
like word clickbait coming into my head
but I think it is important to think
about how to draw people into what can
seem like otherwise esoteric subject
matters and this is something that a lot
of academic writers really struggle with
because I think they've just never had
to imagine writing for a very broad
audience one of the things that's
exciting about letters that we can start
to bring otherwise esoteric concepts to
a much wider audience in a way that
before this technology would have been
difficult to do I'm not sure I'll answer
your question there but I guess the
answer is we we see all kinds of
conversations begin and evolve in
various ways are you making suggestions
to new users about like how to get
started like I just signed up and you
know I've been interested in reaching
out to like some people that I've had
discussions with but as I signed up I
don't remember seeing any like this is
is the best way for you to get started
sort of thing and I just wondered what
your thoughts around that way so this on
the website there's like at all I think
it's a question mark symbol and that has
some very basic tips about how to get
started but we are producing a writers
guide which goes to your question and
something that we need and we've been
reluctant to produce because we really
wanted to see what evolved on the
platform but I think we have enough data
now to say that giving people a
framework to operate from is useful at
least giving them options so this is
these are you know two very distinct
ways to conduct a conversation and it's
it's useful if both parties agree at the
outset as to what type of conversation
they're going to have before they
proceed it's the kind of set
expectations one person might be
thinking while all right three letters
the other person might be thinking well
this can go on forever and it's
important that they're on the same page
there so yeah your question goes to the
hottest something we've been talking
about the last few days actually is it
how much whilst we want to remain non
prescriptive I think we can do a better
job at helping people figure out the
best way to get started for them and
their correspondent thank you thanks to
the cushion also I want to I want to see
a letter between Peter and David on that
topic disembodied stoicism David went
hands down so I don't know I'm gonna
make tap out of that one early Paulette
you had a question about uh privacy
issues yeah so you know we work we often
see writers on on Twitter YouTube what
have you been delisted being attacked
for expressing thoughts or publishing
pictures that are not agreed upon by the
censors and this greatly stifle some
creative thought and um how will this be
addressed in letter in the letter I mean
we self-conscious of what we're writing
in which case we again limit our our
minds or do we just take a chance and
and write expressively hoping that we
won't get censored yeah it's a great
question I think they in all the common
selections our letter our public
I think that's double-edged sword one of
the one of the motivations for creating
leather was because my brother and I had
reached out to some public intellectuals
an email and we're really surprised by
how much well first of all they were
applauded at all but also how much
thought and effort they put into their
replies though it had struck me as kind
of tragic that only one person was
benefiting from what they had written
there in that email I was the odd revert
to sam harris and a few other people and
they actually responded and the idea
that you know there must be millions of
people with similar questions about
their being cut off from that data is
something seems strange about that given
that we have the technology to broadcast
them so I think the public nature is
really important in terms of censorship
we don't intend to censor anything that
isn't the cult of violence I think it's
I mean we're deeply concerned about
what's happening on platforms like
Twitter and Facebook where you know the
the administrators or the sort of
ideological bent of the owners of the
platform affects the data that's shown
so our plan is just to give everything a
lot of day and that the best ideas rise
to the top in terms of how writers
navigate that I think it's important
that you recognize the risks that come
with putting your thoughts out into the
public but also that it
equally if not more risky to sit on
those ideas do one of the things that
does protect people to some extent is
that you can't be affected by an online
Marlon letter there's no comments
there's no interaction it's essentially
like a live event where the two
correspondents are on stage having a
conversation and everyone else is in the
viewing audience and what Twitter has
done is allowed the audience to
interject into their conversation and at
any point so if Twitter is the public
square where anyone can say anything to
anyone about anything then that letter
is the coffee shop you would go to flesh
out your ideas and in a more one-on-one
it's fear except that their audience can
solve use a letter is the star to some
extent that's good coffee shops were
always the place where revolutions began
[Laughter]
amen
all right so Jeff yet a commoner
question yeah just kind of in your
dialogue it's bringing so many things up
and just in terms of you know how you
position things I'm just riffing
extemporaneously but I mean there's some
very famous correspondents relationships
across time like Seneca and Lucilius the
pronunciation or Cicero and Atticus or
Churchill and his wife the common tea
and I wasn't necessarily putting it out
there in order to speak now but just in
terms of the the first part of this
conversation where it sounds like you're
looking now that there's been a good
prototyping period we've gotten a sense
of organically the way that people are
interfacing with the platform providing
some hacks
through historical examples as a frame
so that people can kind of more perhaps
readily kind of sink in into how they
might relate and how they might use the
platform yeah I mean this these are all
ideas that we discussed often and it's a
question of when do you inject features
that nudge nudge the platform in that
direction you know ultimately it would
be fantastic for the knowledge
production happening on letter to exist
in some sort of timeline or for people
to be able to highlight specific
instances where they change their mind
or have their viewers shift in some way
right now that is happening organically
people are sharing the letters and
saying you know my confidence in my
position has changed slightly why now
think slightly differently about this
sort of thing but there is no system
built onto the platform to capture these
examples and kind of I like what you
said about was in the comment and a
brief overview of the significance of
the other correspondence over time yeah
I think that it's really important that
we figure out ways to inject that into
the platform and we've got a bunch of
ideas but those features need to trickle
down onto the platform in lockstep with
what users really want and with that
without distracting from they're fairly
minimalist design and user experience on
there right now I mean one of the things
that it's very important to us is that
the content is given primacy you know
there's not banner ads popping up
there's not a million different features
and different tabs and things to click
on it really is about the conversation
and the ideas and one of the challenges
with technology is that it's so easy to
get excited about all the possibilities
and there
playing the long game and recognizing
what what's the mission and the vision
and how how do we stay true to that as
we add things to add features and
various aspects to the platform is it's
probably the fundamental challenge
because you can Frankenstein a product
to the point where it does everything
for everyone and therefore does nothing
for anyone yeah with everything you just
said when I put that note in the
comments it wasn't to actually
systematize how people would interface
but just in terms of kind of for those
people who are coming to the platform
giving some sort of cultural kind of
insight or some kind of language is just
giving it a sense of the your the nature
of of correspondence in the significance
over time so that people can kind of
click into the headspace of what you
just touched on in terms of how you know
the many different ways in which people
who could operationalize it but just
giving a little bit of kind of the the
soul of the enterprise I think that
there might be some way of going about
that whether it's you know rather than
presenting it as part of say of the
guide perhaps you're more kind of like
you know notes on on the spirits of you
know letter and tracing you know
correspondence over time or just these
are things that are coming to mind as
we're talking yeah I think one way we're
going to be addressing this in the
relative short term is through the
community pages where we will ask the
community leader to write an open letter
to the community and in that letter
would like them to outline what they
hope that community will achieve what's
the call to action here was it important
what questions is this particular
community well positioned to answer and
what kinds of conversations would they
like to see emerge from within it I
think that will help frame
some of the things that you've mentioned
but then we also need to figure out a
way to present that sort of ethos to the
general user it isn't part of a
community on that so yeah these are
challenges that we we haven't sold for
cool I think that was it but we only
have four minutes left so yeah one thing
I'll add to that is when I was matching
people like leaning on my network and
matching people and letter some of
conversations that emerge from there
were like brilliant like John Revathi
and Dave Chapman from me ninis like
those two weren't aware of each other
and people in our sense making web knew
about their geeking out about them so
getting them together was like a huge
deal for not only me a lot of people and
this is why I kind of like want it's
like like weaponize the medic mediators
just to like you know outsource these
these these kind of like people go out
there and make these conversations
happen so we can kick out about them so
if anyone's interested we do yeah but I
mean that happened on this call we
forget sorry who said it but they were
like I would love to see David and Peter
have their conversation and you know one
of the things that we would love to see
more of is organic matchmaking if you
know two people who would have a
fascinating conversation then letters a
great place for them to have it and it
just requires you presenting it to them
and saying I love what you thought here
but I think you might think differently
if you have a conversation with this
person whatever it is that you think
would be the best pitch because
ultimately you're going to be a best
place to make it yeah it's something
that we haven't done enough of we
haven't driven that enough for now I'd
love to see more of that emerge mm-hmm
yeah totally and then David just put
that link there and if you want to join
we have a memetic mediator slack group I
think 100 plus members and then there's
a letter section there where matchmaking
can occur a letter channel on the slack
group so feel free to reach out to me or
David and then we can add to that that
being said any any closing thoughts my
friend
thank you being a pillar you've been
such a amazing driver of content and
attention on two-letter and it's it's
always hard to produce something new
especially online and to get some sort
of traction and you know we rely on
smart writers and curious readers to
grow as any opportunity we can get to
connect with them is deeply appreciated
so thanks for for this opportunity to
speak to this group and I hope to see
you guys on the platform yeah totally
totally so that being said let's see in
closing thoughts yeah so next event we
have a bunch of events tomorrow you can
call on the the web site that we have
Bonita Roy doing her psycho technology
playground collective presidency with
Raya back and then Socratic speed-dating
tomorrow at 7:00 p.m. Eastern Time that
being said the stoah is based off of a
mystical gift economy you could check
out the website for future events that
and for more information League if the
economy and sign up for the mailing list
nothing said Clyde thanks so much
everyone today thank you so much I think
it goes Chiz Hey